very good and welcome one more day to
beta tech in the previous video I received
a lot of comments both on
youtube comments and on twitter that you would
love to see an example of the
programmed code for the collector pattern
so in this video we're going to take
the visual studio editor and we're going to
implement the example that we did in the
previous video the example of enemies
that can wear armor or a helmet or
even a combination of the two to
modify how much damage they receive when they
receive an attack an
enemy that is dressed in armor is not the same as
an enemy that doesn't wear it or an
enemy that wears armor or a helmet
so what we're going to do is
take the structure of the
connector pattern that we defined in the more
theoretical video and really apply it and see how it is
executed and how it is used so without
much further ado let's go directly to the
computer and we're going to implement the
corrector pattern with our
enemies to begin with I say that for
this tutorial I'm going to use text which you already
know that I'm a relative fan of this
programming language I think that for the
web it works very well and that the concept
of types and after programming with
temptation to objects in such a
formal way can help a lot when
learn this design pattern so
to start first of all we are going to
define what would be the main file of
our program like calling it mail
point 3 script basically what we
wanted would be to be able to define an
enemy and we stay with me because here I am
going to implement classes that since they
are not built it is going to start to
complain like never before but we want to be able to
make base enemies for example
create a page enemy and from here
we want to be able to for example look at how much
damage we are going to cause no and imagine
that we have a function called
take damage that defines how many units
of damage we are doing to this
enemy for that we could
simply look at how much damage we have
done by calling the takedown function of
our base enemy instance from
here is where we
want to be able to decorate this enemy
we want to be able to decorate this enemy so that
the damage function does
different things therefore if you
allow me first we are going to create the
beige enemy class to have what would be
our component
this in the theory graph that we made
in the previous video it would be the component
but of course it is still a
concrete component because we are instantiating it no
therefore we have to define its
abstraction the abstraction I am going to
call enemy that being  type script what it's going to
be is going to be an interface
called enemy which is going to implement
or rather define the 30
machine function which as we have said what it's going to
do is return a number that
will determine the damage units that we
are doing to this enemy once
this is defined we can now define what would
be the base enemy the
concrete implementation of the enemy class of the
enemy interface for this we create
a new class which is you see enemy
script point which is
going to be a class that implements the
enemy interface by implementing the
enemy interface as you can see here it is
written it is forcing us to implement
the take damage function because we want it to be able to
behave
anywhere that an enemy is needed that we
are using polymorphism if
we implement the damage function
for example to a base enemy that is to say
an enemy that is not decorated an
enemy that does not wear a helmet or
armor
then we can define that we do about
10 units of damage for example and we
return 10 up to here we
basically have an extraction of enemies
a concrete implementation of the
enemy class and the main function that what it does
is print we have to measure here the
loc
the damage that we have caused to the enemy
if we now execute this main function
we see that what it prints is a 10
because this operation 10
line units from here is where we want to
start with the juice of the
corrector pattern we want to do the part of the
decorators we want to be able to add
things or modify the behavior of
this function take damage of the enemy without
having to reimplement a
specific class of enemy for each possible
combination of decorators no for
example if we had the
helmets decorator of helmet and the armor decorator
of armor then having the
base enemy we would end up having beige enemy
with helmet
or beige enemy with armor or beige
enemy with armor and helmet and helmet that is to
say we have to define all the
possible combinations to avoid this we
can use the corrector pattern
and for that what we would have to do
would obviously be to redefine
an abstraction to define what a
decoration is what is an enemy decorator
to define an enemy decorator
let me create a new class
called enemy of corrector which would be the
abstraction of the decorator if we look at the
graph of the corrector pattern what we
see is that a decorator has  within
itself an enemy and it is
also an enemy what does this mean that
what we have is a class
that by the way I'm going to make abstract
so that it cannot be implemented so that it
cannot be instantiated sorry that is
called enemy connector that we want to be
able to treat as if it were an enemy
to achieve this what we have to
do is that this abstract decorator, that is to
say all the decorators are going to
implement the functions of enemy, that is to
say we can treat any decorator
as if it were an instance of the
enemy class because they implement the same
functionalities as you can see here even
the editor complains to me that we need to be
able to implement the functionalities of
enemy we simply define the function
take the nights that has to return
a number here we would have defined the
inheritance relationship which is what
allows us to be able to use
undecorated enemies or
decorated enemies in a polymorphic way it does not matter to us in the
main if this enemy is a base enemy
or it is an enemy and it has been decorated because the
functions of each match we have for
security by the type system that
is defined what we are missing is
the relationship of having at the end as we have
always said the decorators are like
a kind of layers where the messages
can go transferred
towards  the inside of the onion if we
imagine them as layers of an
onion or even Russian dolls where
each inside each doll we have another
doll just a little bit smaller but the
same so this layer system is what we
have to set up here how do we
set it up basically it's very simple
we can define that the class n measures
coraite or has as an internal attribute
an enemy in this way we have that a
line of collectors is made up of
an internal enemy and that in addition the enemy
decorator is at the same time an enemy therefore
nothing prevents this enemy that we
have inside here from being another enemy
has already decorated this which allows us to
start making layers it would be useful perhaps to
see it as a linked list where the
next item to be treated in the list is
the internal item of the decorator until we
reach the last one which would be the
base enemy so to be able to define the
internal enemy we can do it by the
same constructor we
define a constructor that receives an
enemy as a parameter and seven we master the
enemy to the enemy that we receive
then as this is the base decorator
what I had planned to do is that
this simply returns the
deity mange function of the internal element it is a
decorator that does nothing it does not modify
the behavior but now we're going to
use this abstraction to make a
decorator that does modify the
behavior, let's make for example
the helmet decorator ok let's
make a new class called the gel
mente corrector
which as we said is going to be a child of the
base decorator of the connector enemy and
therefore being a child of the
connector enemy let me put this separately so we
can see both classes at the same time
being a child of the n mini connector we
will have access to the n ming attribute
because this is protected therefore it
has visibility to all its children
and we also inherit these functionalities
and we can override the
constructor there's no need to reimplement it
because the constructor
only creates the
internal element but the take damage function which
is the beauty of it we can
reimplement it if we do and let me
clean this up a bit if we do what we
can implement for example
would be a decorator that what it does is
let's say how do you want to wear helmets are
enemies that cannot be eliminated are
immune enemies ok therefore
what we can do is that it returns 0 it
's a decorator that makes the enemy
not receive any type of damage  so
if we now go to the
main definition and decorate this enemy so
that it has a helmet, which as we have seen
previously we do through the
decorator's constructor we can
define what would be an enemy with a
helmet, an enemy initially,
for which what we do is
instantiate a collector and
pass it the enemy that we want to decorate
with this what we have in enemy
initially is the decorated enemy
therefore if we do the damage calculation
with the decorated enemy and now
we call the main function again what we
see is that it returns 0 it is like a
short circuit let's say we call
the take that might function of the
enemy decorated with the met gel and this
function let's say that it does not depend on what it
has inside it always returns 0
now imagine that what we
want is not to say return
zero the damage is not immune but that by
wearing a helmet they have double the
resistance therefore we make them
half their age what we can do
here would be that instead of returning zero what we do
is return the
damage calculation of what we have below which in
this case as we have seen in main is
the base enemy
which would be this enemy
the damage calculation of  that we have
below and divide it by two this is what it does
is that any enemy that is
decorated with an angel mind
corrector will divide the damage by two
therefore if we now execute
the function we see that it gives us 5 in this
way we can concatenate
decorators to the enemies in a very
generic way we can add layers to them and we
can modify their behavior at
runtime we could do for
example if we give a certain hit to
an enemy we remove the
helmets decorator or for example we add a
decorator that could be for example a
jester or that the speed is not modified
that accelerates our
speed for example it all depends on
what functions we can modify with the
decorator and how we use it to
modify the internal behavior of
these enemies base for completeness of the
example we are going to make the
armor decorator for example when we want to
add a new decorator we can
simply implement a new class
in this case armor collector we
change the name and what
the armor decorator is going to do in this case
well we are going to make it divide 1
by 2 if not by 1.5 that is to say it removes a  a
little more damage not as much as the helmet
but it does take a little more damage off
so if we reopen the main and
the enemy with a helmet we now call it an
enemy with helmet and armor as we
said before a
decorated enemy can behave like a
normal enemy nothing prevents me from
passing the armor decorator
an already decorated enemy to the constructor and
therefore what's going to happen here is that
the effects of each
decorator are going to accumulate if I now run
the min dot cs function again we see
that it has divided by 1 with 5 again
the result of the take damage calculation
this is very useful because what it
allows us is that in the end the
decorated germs and the correct armor
can be used for any type of
enemy if I now want to make a
new enemy that has more life therefore it
has more resistance and
therefore it does not return 10 communities of damage
but in truth it returns well 2
because we do only two units of
damage we can call it the difficult enemy
with this what we get is to be able to
use any type of base enemy
for example our difficult enemy and
decorate it with the same decorators  that we have
already implemented previously
which offers us great flexibility
when defining a complex system or
a system that we want to extend in the
future without having an explosion of
inheritance and enemy classes
an example that I think is very obvious of
defining decorators in
real life would be the functionality the whole
concept of input streams in Java in
Java for example we have the
abstract class input stream which defines the
superclass the abstraction of
all the classes that define a string
of bytes this allows us to
implement the functions of reading
strings of being able to read bytes etcetera
so what Java offers us would be
a definition a set of subclasses
that could be the audio input
stream in the input stream which in this
case the input string would be the component there would be
the role of our
abstract enemy and these would be the
implementations of the input stream that would
play the role of our base enemy
or our significant enemy
would be the daughters of input stream and then we have
the decorators we would
have the base decorator which would be
the filter input stream which as you can
see has an input stream protect &
just like we have defined within
the decorator and it would have the
functions of  read and all the functions
that are also defined in an input
stream because it is
in turn a child of an input stream here
if you look it comes to the base class input
stream which has as a child the filter
input stream which if we are going to see it, in
addition it is not only a child of an input
stream but it also has an input
string inside it is making use of the
correct pattern and if we look at it it
also has classes that inherit from the
filter input testing they inherit from this
decorator therefore for example we
have the bufet input string the safer
input stream the teide input string a
set of decorators that what they do
is surely modify the
behavior of the reading function
in this way to use different
types of sets of
input stream decorators etcetera with java we can and we
have to first instantiate
a specific input stream for example an
audio input screen and then decorate it in
case we want to modify its
functionality and basically the
corrector pattern of this I hope that seeing
real code this has helped you
better understand how the pattern works and
see an example of how it is used in
something like for example the input string of
java I want to emphasize that all this
code  Upload to Git Hub and I'm going to
leave you the link to the description,
so if you want to take a closer look, I'll
leave you the
link right now so you can go to the
repository and check out the code and
much more. See you in the next video.
Bye.